Preliminary Guide to the Albert Rupert Jonsen Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Albert Rupert Jonsen papers
1989-1996
MS 1757
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.25
The papers consist of correspondence, minutes, and other organizational materials relating to Albert R. Jonsen's work on the National Advisory Board on Ethics in Reproduction and the Panel on Monitoring the Social Impact of AIDS of the National Research Council. The papers also include video tapes from the Birth of Bioethics conference held in Seattle in 1992.
Jonsen, Albert R., 1931-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Albert R. Jonsen, 1999.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Biographical / Historical
Albert Rupert Jonsen was born on April 4, 1931 in San Francisco, California. He received B.A. and M.A. degrees from Gonzaga University and earned his doctorate in religious studies from Yale University in 1967. From 1949 until 1976, he was a member of the Society of Jesus. Jonsen taught at the University of San Francisco and the University of California, School of Medicine, before moving in 1987 to the University of Washington where he was chairman of the Department of Medical Ethics in the School of Medicine. Jonsen served as president of the Society for Health and Human Values and was a member of the National Commission for Protection of Human Subjects of Biomedical and Behavioral Research, 1974-1978, and of the President's Commission for the Study of Ethical Problems in Medicine, 1979-1983.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, minutes, and other organizational materials relating to Albert R. Jonsen's work on the National Advisory Board on Ethics in Reproduction and the Panel on Monitoring the Social Impact of AIDS of the National Research Council. The papers also include video tapes from the Birth of Bioethics conference held in Seattle in 1992.
AIDS (Disease); Bioethics; Human reproduction -- Moral and ethical aspects; Medical ethics; Jonsen, Albert R., 1931-; National Advisory Board on Ethics in Reproduction
- Inventory
  - National Advisory Board on Ethics in Reproduction, 1991-1996, undated (Box 1)
  - National Advisory Board on Ethics in Reproduction, 1991-1996, undated (Box 2)
  - National Advisory Board on Ethics in Reproduction, 1991-1996, undated (Box 3)
  - National Research Council. Panel on Monitoring the Social Impact of AIDS, 1989-1994, undated (Box 3)
  - Birth of Bioethics conference, 1992 Sep 23 -24
    - 11 T60 videocassettes with log, 1992 (Box 4)
    - 3 T60, 1 T120, and 1 T30 videocassettes, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
  - Selection for Dialysis--2 T120 videocassettes and 1 audiocassette, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Unidentified audiocassette, undated (Box 5)